[
    {
        "Question":"A 24-year-old male with a history of recurrent perianal fistulas in the previous  year is not responding to the management of whatever surgical or medical  treatment, what is the most likely underlying cause?",
        "Option 1":"Crohn's Colitis",
        "Option 2":"Diverticular disease",
        "Option 3":"Ulcerative Colitis",
        "Option 4":"Right colon cancer",
        "Option 5":"Left colon cancer",
        "Correct Answer":"Crohn's Colitis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 64-year-old man presented at your surgery complaining of rectal bleeding  and abdominal pain. Colonoscopy was done and revealed multiple intestinal  hamartomas. During the examination, you noticed multiple pigmentation spots  around his mouth. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Familial adenomatous polyposis syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Cowden disease",
        "Option 3":"MYH-associated polyposis.",
        "Option 4":"Peutz-Jeghers syndrome",
        "Option 5":"Lynch syndrome",
        "Correct Answer":"Peutz-Jeghers syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25-year-old man presents with severe constipation and anal bleeding after taking opiate analgesics for chronic pain. Which of the following is the most likely description of his rectal bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Dark red with watery diarrhea",
        "Option 2":"Bright red with severe perianal pain",
        "Option 3":"Bright red profuse bleeding with hemodynamic instability",
        "Option 4":"Dark red mixed with stool",
        "Option 5":"Dark red with an offensive odour",
        "Correct Answer":"Bright red with severe perianal pain"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old man who had been diagnosed with familial adenomatous polyposis and underwent a total colectomy 30 years earlier. Nowadays, the patient presents with a three-week history of painless jaundice with the passage of pale stools, dark urine, anorexia, weight loss and vomiting. What is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Carcinoma of the duodenum",
        "Option 2":"Gastric carcinoma",
        "Option 3":"Hepatitis C",
        "Option 4":"Hepatocellular carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Primary biliary cirrhosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Carcinoma of the duodenum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the type of lymphoma associated with coeliac disease?",
        "Option 1":"T-cell lymphoma",
        "Option 2":"B-cell Lymphoma",
        "Option 3":"Burkitt's lymphoma",
        "Option 4":"Mantle cell lymphoma",
        "Option 5":"Hodgkin's lymphoma",
        "Correct Answer":"T-cell lymphoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 40-year-old patient presented with abdominal pain, flushing and diarrhoea. He underwent an appendectomy 2 days ago. The histopathological examination revealed a 4 cm carcinoid. What is the next investigation?",
        "Option 1":"Abdominal CT scan with contrast",
        "Option 2":"Urinary 5-HIAA",
        "Option 3":"Abdominal USS",
        "Option 4":"Abdominal MRI",
        "Option 5":"Abdominal CT scan without contrast",
        "Correct Answer":"Urinary 5-HIAA"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old patient was diagnosed with FAP and his biopsy follow showed high-grade dysplastic changes a management planed is for prophylactic pan- proctocolectomy and stoma formation, what type of stoma will you use?",
        "Option 1":"End ileostomy",
        "Option 2":"End colostomy",
        "Option 3":"loop ileostomy",
        "Option 4":"loop colostomy",
        "Option 5":"Ileal pouch and anal anastomosis",
        "Correct Answer":"End ileostomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 20-year-old man presents with a 2-day history of acute anal pain and fever.  The patient cannot tolerate rectal examination. He was diagnosed with a perianal  abscess. What is the best treatment?",
        "Option 1":"incision and primary closure",
        "Option 2":"Incision and drainage",
        "Option 3":"Topical steroids",
        "Option 4":"IV antibiotics",
        "Option 5":"Injection with 88% aqueous phenol",
        "Correct Answer":"Incision and drainage"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient presented to the surgical unit with a rectal mass and was diagnosed  with rectal carcinoma to which of the following sites will a metastatic lesion be  found first?",
        "Option 1":"Lung",
        "Option 2":"Bone",
        "Option 3":"Liver",
        "Option 4":"Brain",
        "Option 5":"Colon",
        "Correct Answer":"Liver"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is not considered a predisposing factor to cancer colon?",
        "Option 1":"Chron\u2019s disease",
        "Option 2":"Alcohol",
        "Option 3":"Smoking",
        "Option 4":"Diverticular disease",
        "Option 5":"Genetic causes",
        "Correct Answer":"Diverticular disease"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old male presents to the A&E complaining of absolute constipation and persistent vomiting for the past 2 days. His investigation showed HB of 7 mg and a mass on the Caecum with dilatation of the small bowel up to 4 cm in diameter. What is the best action?",
        "Option 1":"Elective Right Hemicolectomy",
        "Option 2":"Urgent laparotomy, Right Hemicolectomy, and ileostomy",
        "Option 3":"Only Ileostomy",
        "Option 4":"Urgent laparotomy and Right Hemicolectomy",
        "Option 5":"Support general condition and refer to Chemoradiotherapy",
        "Correct Answer":"Urgent laparotomy and Right Hemicolectomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 19-year-old female presents with severe anal pain and bleeding which  occurs post-defecation. On examination, she has a posteriorly sited fissure in ano  what is the initial treatment?",
        "Option 1":"Excision and primary closure",
        "Option 2":"Topical steroids",
        "Option 3":"Topical diltiazem",
        "Option 4":"Manual anal dilation",
        "Option 5":"Sphincterotomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Topical diltiazem"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 43-year-old male has been troubled with symptoms of post-defecation  bleeding for many years. On examination, he has large, prolapsed haemorrhoids,  colonoscopy shows no other disease. What is the best treatment?",
        "Option 1":"Excision and primary closure",
        "Option 2":"Topical steroids",
        "Option 3":"Hemorrhoidectomy",
        "Option 4":"Injection with 88% aqueous phenol",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Hemorrhoidectomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the gene involved in cases of Familial polyposis coli?",
        "Option 1":"DNA repair gene",
        "Option 2":"STK11 gene",
        "Option 3":"APC gene",
        "Option 4":"PTEN gene",
        "Option 5":"BRCA1",
        "Correct Answer":"APC gene"
    },
    {
        "Question":"57 years old with a 5-month history of constipation and dark bleeding, the colonoscope showed a Localized Annular ca sigmoid colon, with no METs. What is the best type of surgery to do as an emergent operation?",
        "Option 1":"left colectomy and anastomosis",
        "Option 2":"Left hemicolectomy",
        "Option 3":"Hartman",
        "Option 4":"Ileostomy",
        "Option 5":"APR",
        "Correct Answer":"Hartman"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient 56-year-old presented with recurrent attacks of UTI,  pneumaturia, and irregular bowel habits. CT showed a mass in both the sigmoid and bladder, what is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Diverticulosis",
        "Option 2":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Option 3":"Chron's disease",
        "Option 4":"Cancer colon",
        "Option 5":"Meckel's diverticulitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Diverticulosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old man presents with absolute constipation and abdominal pain.  On examination, he has marked abdominal distension. A digital rectal  examination reveals an empty rectum. A rectal contrast study shows an  obstructing lesion of the proximal rectum. What is the best intervention?",
        "Option 1":"High anterior resection",
        "Option 2":"Low anterior resection",
        "Option 3":"Loop colostomy of the transverse colon",
        "Option 4":"Loop colostomy of the sigmoid",
        "Option 5":"Loop ileostomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Loop colostomy of the sigmoid"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55 year old patient with perforated sigmoid diverticulum planned for hartman\u2019s procedure. What is the stoma type will you design?",
        "Option 1":"End ileostomy",
        "Option 2":"End colostomy",
        "Option 3":"Loop ileostomy",
        "Option 4":"Loop colostomy",
        "Option 5":"Gastrostomy",
        "Correct Answer":"End colostomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient had small bowel resection five days ago. He became feverish with abdominal pain. The nurse calls you and notices a serosanginous discharge form the wound, what is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Wound infection",
        "Option 2":"Anastomotic leak",
        "Option 3":"Necrotizing fasciitis",
        "Option 4":"Gas gangrene",
        "Option 5":"Abscess",
        "Correct Answer":"Anastomotic leak"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An 18-year-old man presented to the outpatient clinic complaining of severe  agonizing pain post defecation with bleeding of fresh blood. He gave a history of  untreated chronic constipation. Which of the following is most probable cause of  his complaint?",
        "Option 1":"Abscess",
        "Option 2":"Hemorrhoids",
        "Option 3":"Fissure in ano",
        "Option 4":"IBD",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Fissure in ano"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following sites is least likely to develop diverticulosis?",
        "Option 1":"Caecum",
        "Option 2":"Rectum",
        "Option 3":"Transverse colon",
        "Option 4":"Ascending colon",
        "Option 5":"Sigmoid colon",
        "Correct Answer":"Rectum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Primary sclerosing cholangitis is associated with?",
        "Option 1":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Option 2":"Chron's disease",
        "Option 3":"Cancer colon",
        "Option 4":"Diverticulosis",
        "Option 5":"IBS",
        "Correct Answer":"Ulcerative colitis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient was recently diagnosed with colonic cancer and underwent a surgery. The pathology report came back as Duke\u2019s B. what is the 5 years survival in this patient?",
        "Option 1":"90%",
        "Option 2":"40%",
        "Option 3":"30%",
        "Option 4":"70%",
        "Option 5":"5%",
        "Correct Answer":"70%"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old male resented with intestinal obstruction and was diagnosed as  having malignant obstruction of the right colon. Surgical resection done and the  pathology report shows that the malignancy involves all the submucosa with no  invasion of the muscularis propria and 2 nodes out of 24 are positive. PET scan  showed that there are no Mets. What is the TNM classification of the condition?",
        "Option 1":"T1N0M0",
        "Option 2":"T1N1M1",
        "Option 3":"T1N1M0",
        "Option 4":"TN1M0",
        "Option 5":"T3N1M0",
        "Correct Answer":"T1N1M0"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 67-year-old man is admitted with a history of fresh rectal bleeding preceded  by left-sided abdominal pain on two occasions in the past 36 hours. The blood  was both bright red and dark plum colored mixed with a loose motion.  Examination shows frank blood per rectum. There is slight abdominal tenderness  in the left upper quadrant and left iliac fossa. He is normotensive with a  hemoglobin of 106 g\/L. Xray shows a thumbprint sign. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Anal carcinoma",
        "Option 2":"Ischemic colitis",
        "Option 3":"Meckel diverticulum",
        "Option 4":"Oesophageal varices",
        "Option 5":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Ischemic colitis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45-year-old man is admitted with a history of sudden fresh rectal bleeding with a huge amount of blood loss that led the patient to be confused. The patient and his relatives denied any similar attacks in the past. Examination shows frank blood per rectum with slight abdominal tenderness and Hg Drop. Patient Pulse is 110 beat and BP 90-60. which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Anal carcinoma",
        "Option 2":"Ischemic colitis",
        "Option 3":"Angiodysplasia of the colon",
        "Option 4":"Oesophageal varices",
        "Option 5":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Angiodysplasia of the colon"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 30-year-old man is admitted with right iliac fossa pain and tenderness. He alleged that the pain is increasing over the past 3 days, plus he complained of attacks of diarrhea and constipation over the past 5 months. Patient HB is 9. And vital stable. which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Crohn's disease",
        "Option 2":"Ischemic colitis",
        "Option 3":"Acute Appendicitis",
        "Option 4":"Meckel diverticulum",
        "Option 5":"Irritable bowel syndrome",
        "Correct Answer":"Crohn's disease"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In a patient with Menetriers disease. What is the possible complication?",
        "Option 1":"Hyperacidity",
        "Option 2":"Hypoalbuminemia",
        "Option 3":"Decrease Vitamin B12",
        "Option 4":"Gastric Cancer",
        "Option 5":"Electrolyte imbalance",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypoalbuminemia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old female is admitted with a history of passing brown-colored urine and abdominal distension. On examination, she clinically got large bowel obstruction with central abdominal tenderness. She is maximally tender in the left iliac fossa. The is no evidence of hemodynamic instability. What is the most appropriate investigation?",
        "Option 1":"Cystogram",
        "Option 2":"Abdominal X-ray of the kidney, ureters, and bladder",
        "Option 3":"Computerized tomogram of the abdomen and pelvis",
        "Option 4":"Flexible sigmoidoscopy",
        "Option 5":"Barium enema",
        "Correct Answer":"Computerized tomogram of the abdomen and pelvis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 32-year-old with abdominal pain, constipation and severe weight loss he diagnosed ha cancer caecum, and the rest of the colon is filled with polyps. He has a positive Family history of similar condition and his mother died from cancer stomach. What is the best plan of management to this patient?",
        "Option 1":"Right hemicolectomy",
        "Option 2":"Pan proctocolectomy",
        "Option 3":"Extended hemicolectomy",
        "Option 4":"Chemotherapy",
        "Option 5":"Ilio-transverse bypass",
        "Correct Answer":"Pan proctocolectomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 53-year-old man presents with a full thickness external rectal prolapse. Which of the following procedures would be the most suitable surgical option?",
        "Option 1":"Rectopexy",
        "Option 2":"Delormes",
        "Option 3":"Altmeirs",
        "Option 4":"Thirsch tape",
        "Option 5":"Abdomino-perineal excision of the rectum",
        "Correct Answer":"Rectopexy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient 67 years old complained of recurrent attacks of UTI, pneumaturia, and irregular bowel habits associated with rectal bleeding. CT shown mass involved both the sigmoid and bladder, what is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Diverticulosis",
        "Option 2":"Cancer sigmoid",
        "Option 3":"IBS",
        "Option 4":"UC",
        "Option 5":"Chron's disease",
        "Correct Answer":"Diverticulosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which statement is the best description for a Duke's C cancer colon?",
        "Option 1":"Involvement of paraaortic lymph nodes",
        "Option 2":"Direct local invasion of urinary bladder",
        "Option 3":"Localized tumor to mucosa and submucosa",
        "Option 4":"Free lymph node with invasion of musculosa",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Involvement of paraaortic lymph nodes"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old patient with ulcerative colitis complaining of peritonitis and bowel perforation. Surgeons decide to perform an ileostomy. After 6 months he developed skin ulceration and nodules around stoma site. what is the name of these ulcers?",
        "Option 1":"Erythema nodosum",
        "Option 2":"Pyoderma gangrenosum",
        "Option 3":"Necrotizing fasciitis",
        "Option 4":"Squamous cell carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Contact Ulcer",
        "Correct Answer":"Pyoderma gangrenosum"
    },
    {
        "Question":"8-year-old boy with chronic constipation for a long period and he presented  now complaining of a very agonizing pain from the anus associated with brisk  fresh blood at the end of defecation, what is your provisional diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Juvenile polyp",
        "Option 2":"Anal Hemorrhoids",
        "Option 3":"Intussusception",
        "Option 4":"Anal fissure",
        "Option 5":"Perianal abscess",
        "Correct Answer":"Anal fissure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 30-year-old woman presents to the outpatient' clinic with a three-month  history of diarrhea, which is intermittently bloody. On rectal biopsy, the histology  has shown' a granulomatous inflammation. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Amoebiasis",
        "Option 2":"Crohn's disease",
        "Option 3":"Sarcoidosis",
        "Option 4":"Tuberculosis",
        "Option 5":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Crohn's disease"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most common cause of mesenteric infarction?",
        "Option 1":"Mesenteric vein thrombosis",
        "Option 2":"Acute embolism affecting the superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Acute on top of chronic thrombus of the superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"Subintimal dissection of the superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 5":"Proximal migration of abdominal aortic aneurysm",
        "Correct Answer":"Acute embolism affecting the superior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 78-year-old man has undergone a hemi-arthroplasty for an intracapsular hip fracture. Post operatively he develops electrolyte derangement and receives intravenous fluids. Over the next 24 hours he develops marked abdominal distension. On examination, he has a tense, tympanic abdomen which is not painful. A contrast enema shows flow of contrast through to the caecum and through the ileocecal valve. What is the most likely cause?",
        "Option 1":"Ogilvies syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Diverticular stricture",
        "Option 3":"Malignant stricture",
        "Option 4":"Volvulus",
        "Option 5":"Adhesive obstruction",
        "Correct Answer":"Ogilvies syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 68-year-old man presented by acute abdomen and peritonitis after investigation patient diagnosed as sigmoid perforation. By examination pulse 120 BP 90-60 and RR 17. What is the best intervention?",
        "Option 1":"Ileostomy Only",
        "Option 2":"Resection and ileostomy",
        "Option 3":"Hartman's procedure",
        "Option 4":"Diverting ileostomy with colorectal anastomosis",
        "Option 5":"Ileoanal anastomosis and diverting colostomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Hartman's procedure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"70 years old undergo routine checkup of colonoscopy, but it can't pass beyond hepatic flexure. What is the best investigation to use?",
        "Option 1":"CT Colonography",
        "Option 2":"CT without contrast",
        "Option 3":"Re use colonoscope",
        "Option 4":"MRI Abdomen",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"CT Colonography"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55 year old patient complaining of recurrent complicated perianal fistulae over the past 3 years, what is the best modality of investigation that we help you to delineate the course of the fistula?",
        "Option 1":"CT Scan of the Pelvis",
        "Option 2":"Superficial Us",
        "Option 3":"Fistulogram",
        "Option 4":"MRI scan of the pelvis",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"MRI scan of the pelvis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient is presented with right hypochondrial pain. Investigations revealed multiple stones in bile ducts. This can be associated with which of the following bowel disorders?",
        "Option 1":"Crohn's disease",
        "Option 2":"Diverticulitis",
        "Option 3":"Meckel's diverticulum",
        "Option 4":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Crohn's disease"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male 35 years old presented with tender fluctuate perianal and rectal swelling,  he is feverish for that past 2 days and cannot tolerate PR examination. What is  the most appropriate treatment?",
        "Option 1":"Incision of this swelling and primary closure",
        "Option 2":"Excision of this swelling",
        "Option 3":"Hemorrhoidectomy",
        "Option 4":"Medical Treatment",
        "Option 5":"Incision of the swelling and lay open",
        "Correct Answer":"Incision of the swelling and lay open"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with a right iliac fossa mass and investigations confirmed  a caecal cancer. He underwent resection. The resected specimen was reported as  T4, what does this mean?",
        "Option 1":"Involving surrounding abdominal musculature",
        "Option 2":"Multiple lesions in the resected specimen",
        "Option 3":"Muscularis propria Invasion",
        "Option 4":"Lymphatic or vascular Invasion",
        "Option 5":"Involvement of liver or lung",
        "Correct Answer":"Involving surrounding abdominal musculature"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 28-year-old male patient presented to the surgical unit 3 months post  colostomy reversal that was done as a treatment for a perforated viscus. He now  presents with severe abdominal pain, vomiting and swelling at the stoma site  which of the following is the reason for that?",
        "Option 1":"Wound dehiscence",
        "Option 2":"intestinal obstruction",
        "Option 3":"Incarcerated incisional hernia",
        "Option 4":"Wound infection",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Incarcerated incisional hernia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 48-year-old woman presents with abdominal pain and five to six episodes of  bloody diarrhea each day. She also complains of pain- in the knees and elbows  and recent visual problems. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Collagenous colitis",
        "Option 2":"Diverticulitis",
        "Option 3":"Infective colitis",
        "Option 4":"Intestinal tuberculosis",
        "Option 5":"Ulcerative colitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Ulcerative colitis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old female is admitted with a history of passing brown colored urine and abdominal distension. On examination, she is clinically got large bowel obstruction with central abdominal tenderness. She is maximally tender in the left iliac fossa. The is no evidence of hemodynamic instability. What is the most appropriate investigation?",
        "Option 1":"Cystogram",
        "Option 2":"Abdominal X-ray of the kidney, ureters, and bladder",
        "Option 3":"Computerized tomogram of the abdomen and pelvis",
        "Option 4":"Flexible sigmoidoscopy",
        "Option 5":"Barium enema",
        "Correct Answer":"Computerized tomogram of the abdomen and pelvis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 27 year old gas had pancolitis for the last five years. Which one of these complications is the least likely to develop?",
        "Option 1":"Arthritis",
        "Option 2":"Cholangitis",
        "Option 3":"Iritis",
        "Option 4":"Polyarteritis",
        "Option 5":"Toxic megacolon",
        "Correct Answer":"Polyarteritis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 69-year man with recta! cancer undergoes low anterior resection. The liver is disease free. The pathology of his tumour was reported as a large tumour invading from the rectum into the mesorectum. Two nodes of 24 lymph nodes, close to the tumour were carcinoma on histology. The tumour was completely excised. What is the correct pathological staging of his tumour?",
        "Option 1":"Dukes' A",
        "Option 2":"Dukes' B",
        "Option 3":"Dukes' C",
        "Option 4":"Dukes' D",
        "Option 5":"Dukes' C",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 49-year-old lady presents with a 36-hour history of absolute constipation. A CT scan is performed and demonstrates an obstructing T3 tumor of the distal descending colon, there is no evidence of distant visceral metastatic disease.",
        "Option 1":"Insertion of self-expanding metallic stent",
        "Option 2":"Left hemicolectomy and on-table colonic lavage",
        "Option 3":"Extended right hemicolectomy and ileocolic anastomosis",
        "Option 4":"Loop colostomy of the transverse colon",
        "Option 5":"Loop colostomy of the sigmoid colon",
        "Correct Answer":"Left hemicolectomy and on-table colonic lavage"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old lady presents with a two-day history of constipation and vomiting. On examination, she has right iliac fossa tenderness and little abdominal distension. A CT scan is performed and is suggestive of an obstructing carcinoma of the colonic hepatic flexure (stage T3). What is the best action?",
        "Option 1":"Ileocolic bypass",
        "Option 2":"High anterior resection",
        "Option 3":"Insertion of self-expanding metallic stent",
        "Option 4":"Extended right hemicolectomy and ileocolic anastomosis",
        "Option 5":"Right hemicolectomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Right hemicolectomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 25-year guy underwent Pan proctocolectomy for UC as an elective procedure and the patient refuse the diversion, what is the best action?",
        "Option 1":"Ileoanal pouch",
        "Option 2":"Hartman's procedure",
        "Option 3":"Ileoanal anastomosis and diverting colostomy",
        "Option 4":"Cecostomy",
        "Option 5":"End colostomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Ileoanal pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 70-year-old man presented with cancer colon plus Liver Mets (2 foci in the liver), he proceeded for a surgical operation to resect the colon, what is the best action for the liver Mets?",
        "Option 1":"Chemotherapy to downstage the tumor and then resection",
        "Option 2":"Resection from the start",
        "Option 3":"No intervention and follow-up.",
        "Option 4":"Alcohol injection",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Chemotherapy to downstage the tumor and then resection"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patient presented with rectal polyps by examination he has spots around the  mouth and mostly is diagnosed as Peut Jughers $. what is the type of these  polyps?",
        "Option 1":"Hamartomata",
        "Option 2":"Adenomatous",
        "Option 3":"Hyperplasia",
        "Option 4":"Malignant",
        "Option 5":"Benign polyp",
        "Correct Answer":"Hamartomata"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An elderly patient came with large fresh rectal bleeding which cannot be  controlled with conservative measurement, what is the next option?",
        "Option 1":"CT Angiography",
        "Option 2":"Colonoscopy",
        "Option 3":"CT Abdomen & pelvis with contrast",
        "Option 4":"Follow up",
        "Option 5":"Abdominal US",
        "Correct Answer":"CT Angiography"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 72-year-old patient with an umbilicated mass was seen by the Gl endoscopy  over the greater curvature of the stomach. A biopsy is inconclusive. The lesion is  well circumscribed with intact mucosal service. What is the most accepted  diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Adenocarcinoma",
        "Option 2":"Adenoma",
        "Option 3":"GIST",
        "Option 4":"Signet ring carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Lienitis plastica",
        "Correct Answer":"GIST"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 75-year-old long-term psychiatric patient presented to the A&E with left  lower abdominal pain and severe abdominal distension with no history of  defecation over the past 5 days. What is the most appropriate diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Sigmoid volvulus",
        "Option 2":"Caecal volvulus",
        "Option 3":"Appendicitis",
        "Option 4":"Ischemic colitis",
        "Option 5":"Diverticulitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Sigmoid volvulus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following medications may be used in cases of carcinoid?",
        "Option 1":"Dexamethasone",
        "Option 2":"B-blocker",
        "Option 3":"Anti-histaminic",
        "Option 4":"Octreotide",
        "Option 5":"Carbimazole",
        "Correct Answer":"Octreotide"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 40-year-old man presents with obstructive jaundice. Twenty years  previously he underwent a right hemicolectomy for a mucinous right-sided colonic carcinoma. He was subsequently diagnosed as having Lynch syndrome  What is the most likely cause of his jaundice?",
        "Option 1":"Hepatocellular carcinoma",
        "Option 2":"Liver metastasis from colonic cancer",
        "Option 3":"Pancreatic carcinoma",
        "Option 4":"Duodenal carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Gastric carcinoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastric carcinoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old male diagnosed with Barrett's esophagus after a long history  of epigastric pain. On follow-up endoscopy you discovered a nodule of 1 cm in  diameter, Histopathology revealed a high-grade dysplasia. CT scan done and  showed that there is no invasion of the surrounding structures or lymph nodes  Mets. What is the best course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Follow-up endoscopy",
        "Option 2":"Surgical resection",
        "Option 3":"Endoscopic mucosal resection",
        "Option 4":"Esophageal stent",
        "Option 5":"Chemoradiotherapy",
        "Correct Answer":"Endoscopic mucosal resection"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An 81-year-old is male was admitted in ICU for the last 40 day due to  pneumonia. Today the patient started to develop dysphagia. What is the most  accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Esophageal web",
        "Option 2":"Reflux",
        "Option 3":"Candida infection",
        "Option 4":"Cancer esophagus",
        "Option 5":"Achalasia",
        "Correct Answer":"Candida infection"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old man presented with a history of progressive dysphagia over the past 4 weeks. His health records showed that he has symptoms of dyspepsia and reflux over the past 5 years. What is the most accepted cause for dysphagia?",
        "Option 1":"Oesophageal candidiasis",
        "Option 2":"Carcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Achalasia",
        "Option 4":"Hiatus hernia",
        "Option 5":"Esophageal reflux",
        "Correct Answer":"Carcinoma of the esophagus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An alcoholic man admitted with severe chest pain and hematemesis which occurs after vigorous attack of vomiting. On examination he has crepitations in the anterior chest wall. What is the most probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Complete esophageal rupture",
        "Option 2":"Mallory Weiss tear",
        "Option 3":"Pneumothorax",
        "Option 4":"Fracture ribs",
        "Option 5":"Rupture bronchus",
        "Correct Answer":"Complete esophageal rupture"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old man complaining of odynophagia, severe weight loss and hematemesis. The upper GI endoscope showed fleshy mass on the middle third of the esophagus. Histopathology reveals SCC and the metastatic follow-up showed no Mets. What is the best action?",
        "Option 1":"Segmental resection",
        "Option 2":"Ivor-Lewis",
        "Option 3":"Chemo and radiotherapy",
        "Option 4":"Follow-up",
        "Option 5":"Laser ablation",
        "Correct Answer":"Chemo and radiotherapy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"52-year-old women required a partial gastrectomy for a large benign ulcer in  his gastric antrum. After six months she complains of palpitations and sweating in  addition to an abdominal pain which occurs within an hour of meals. Usually,  symptoms subsides after less have an hour. What is the most likely cause of her  symptom pattern?",
        "Option 1":"Gastroparesis",
        "Option 2":"Dumping syndrome",
        "Option 3":"Delayed gastric emptying",
        "Option 4":"Peptic ulceration",
        "Option 5":"Electrolyte disturbance",
        "Correct Answer":"Dumping syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 76-year-old man presents with a 5-week history of progressive dysphagia  to solids more than liquids. The surgeon notice that there is a fleshy mass protruding in the middle part of the esophagus with a necrotic surface during  upper endoscopy. What is the most probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Mallory Weiss Tear",
        "Option 2":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Adenocarcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 4":"Peptic stricture",
        "Option 5":"Achalasia",
        "Correct Answer":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A male patient 50-year-old complaining of sweating, palpitations, and convulsions after sleeve bariatric. What would you suggest the patient do?",
        "Option 1":"Advice to eat regular small meals.",
        "Option 2":"Supplement meals with protein and glucose intake",
        "Option 3":"Just follow up.",
        "Option 4":"Vagotomy",
        "Option 5":"Gastric bypass surgery",
        "Correct Answer":"Advice to eat regular small meals."
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 62-year-old male presented to the A&E department with massive oral bleeding. On examination he has hepatosplenomegaly. Patient now is unconscious with BP at 80-70 mmHg. What is the most common cause of bleeding?",
        "Option 1":"Rupture esophageal varices",
        "Option 2":"Rupture esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Bleeding gastric ulcer",
        "Option 4":"Coagulopathy disorder",
        "Option 5":"Bleeding duodenal ulcer",
        "Correct Answer":"Rupture esophageal varices"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old has been complaining of a benign esophageal stricture which  managed by placing esophageal stent 2 years ago. Now, he presented with  dysphagia and retrosternal chest pain. What is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Infection on the stent",
        "Option 2":"Development of malignancy",
        "Option 3":"Bolus Impaction",
        "Option 4":"Stent migration",
        "Option 5":"Fibrosis on stent",
        "Correct Answer":"Stent migration"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 22-year-old man presents with a 5-month history of episodic retrosternal chest  pain as well as episodes of dysphagia to liquids. An upper GI endoscopy is  performed, and no mucosal abnormality detected. What is the most accepted  diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Mallory Weiss Tear",
        "Option 2":"Hiatus hernia",
        "Option 3":"Peptic stricture",
        "Option 4":"Motility disorder",
        "Option 5":"Esophageal carcinoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Motility disorder"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 72-year-old man diagnosed with esophageal adenocarcinoma after a  progressive dysphagia. His staging investigations revealed a metastatic lesion in  the right lobe of the liver. What is the best appropriate course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Trans hiatal Esophagectomy",
        "Option 2":"Ivor Lewis Esophagectomy",
        "Option 3":"Endoscopic sub mucosal dissection",
        "Option 4":"Photodynamic therapy",
        "Option 5":"Endoscopic stent",
        "Correct Answer":"Endoscopic stent"
    },
    {
        "Question":"14. A 35-year-old male with severe hematemesis, underwent urgent UGI  endoscopy that show a large bleeding ulcer in the 1st part duodenum. The surgeon  injected adrenaline and used hemostatic clips in a trial to stop bleeding, but this  was unsuccessful. What to do next?",
        "Option 1":"Follow Up",
        "Option 2":"Laparotomy and surgical resection",
        "Option 3":"Laparotomy and underrunning suture",
        "Option 4":"IV Vit-K",
        "Option 5":"CT Angiogram",
        "Correct Answer":"Laparotomy and underrunning suture"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60-year-old male patient underwent distal gastrectomy with anterior  gastrojejunostomy due to distal gastric carcinoma, he presented 2 year later complaining of weight loss and repeated vomiting. He was diagnosed with delayed gastric emptying, what is best intervention for this patient?",
        "Option 1":"Re-fashioning this anterior gastrojejunostomy",
        "Option 2":"Posterior gastrojejunostomy",
        "Option 3":"Roux En-Y design",
        "Option 4":"Balloon dilatation of the anastomosis",
        "Option 5":"Distal jejunostomy",
        "Correct Answer":"Roux En-Y design"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old male with a history of esophagectomy and anastomosis.  Presented complaining of progressive dysphagia. On examination there is no  weight loss or palpable masses in the abdomen. A barium study showed a stenotic  segment of 2 cm in the middle part of the esophagus. What is the best  intervention?",
        "Option 1":"Surgical resection",
        "Option 2":"balloon dilatation",
        "Option 3":"Botulinum injection",
        "Option 4":"Medical treatment",
        "Option 5":"No intervention needed",
        "Correct Answer":"balloon dilatation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An alcoholic man drunk all over the previous night and now came with 200ml  fresh bleeding per month after vigorous vomiting. What Is the most probable  diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Candida esophagus",
        "Option 2":"Carcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Mallory Weiss",
        "Option 4":"Esophageal rupture",
        "Option 5":"Peptic esophagus",
        "Correct Answer":"Mallory Weiss"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A45-year-old man presented with tachycardia and bilateral ankle edema. On examination there was enlarged supraclavicular lymph node. His investigation showed iron deficiency anemia and positive occult blood in the stool. What is the most probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Esophageal cancer",
        "Option 2":"Bronchial cancer",
        "Option 3":"Cecal cancer",
        "Option 4":"Gastric carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Lymphoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastric carcinoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45-year-old woman who is on vitamin B12 injection for treatment of macrocytic anemia. She has a 3 months history of vomiting dark blood, weight loss, microcytic hypochromic anemia and positive occult blood in the stool. What is the probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Esophageal cancer",
        "Option 2":"Bronchial cancer",
        "Option 3":"Cecal cancer",
        "Option 4":"Gastric carcinoma",
        "Option 5":"Lymphoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Gastric carcinoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 76-year-old man presented with a one-month history of progressive  dysphagia. An upper GI endoscopy is performed, the esophagus is filled with food  debris and the endoscope encounters a resistance and cannot pass. The  endoscopist noticed there are many areas of Barrett's esophagus. What is the  most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Mallory Weiss Tear",
        "Option 2":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Adenocarcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 4":"Peptic stricture",
        "Option 5":"Achalasia",
        "Correct Answer":"Adenocarcinoma of the esophagus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the best investigation in cases of Boerhaave syndrome?",
        "Option 1":"Upper GI Endoscope",
        "Option 2":"Barium Swallow",
        "Option 3":"Chest X ray",
        "Option 4":"CT Chest",
        "Option 5":"MRI chest",
        "Correct Answer":"CT Chest"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient 39-year-old presented with sudden chest pain and hematemesis which occurs after aggressive vomiting. On examination he has crepitus sensation over the upper chest, what is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Mallory Weiss syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Boerhaave syndrome",
        "Option 3":"Rupture trachea",
        "Option 4":"Rupture Zenker diverticulum",
        "Option 5":"Rupture pulmonary plebs",
        "Correct Answer":"Boerhaave syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 40-year-old man presented complaining of dysphagia for many months, Esophageal manometry showed lack of relaxation of the lower esophageal sphincter during swallowing. What is the most accepted cause for dysphagia?",
        "Option 1":"Globus",
        "Option 2":"Carcinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Achalasia",
        "Option 4":"Hiatus hernia",
        "Option 5":"Esophageal fibrosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Achalasia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 58-year-old lady has a 2-year history of worsening dysphagia. In addition, she has  been complaining of nocturnal cough and epigastric discomfort for many years.  Recently, she has lost a total of 8kg in weight. Which of the processes below is the  most likely explanation for this?",
        "Option 1":"Gastro-esophageal reflux disease",
        "Option 2":"Barrett's esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Esophageal Carcinoma",
        "Option 4":"Mallory Weiss tear",
        "Option 5":"Esophageal infection",
        "Correct Answer":"Esophageal Carcinoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 58 male patient proceeded for an upper endoscopy a day before, he presented  with fever at 39, chest pain, and shortness of breathing and an x-ray showed a wide  mediastinum. What is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Empyema",
        "Option 2":"Mediastinitis",
        "Option 3":"Lung abscess",
        "Option 4":"Aortic aneurism",
        "Option 5":"Aspiration pneumonia",
        "Correct Answer":"Mediastinitis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An alcoholic man drink all over the previous night and now come with 500ml fresh bleeding per mouth at the A&E. What Is the most probable Diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Candida esophagus",
        "Option 2":"Cardinoma of the esophagus",
        "Option 3":"Mallory Weiss",
        "Option 4":"Complete esophageal rupture",
        "Option 5":"Peptic esophogus",
        "Correct Answer":"Mallory Weiss"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the investigation of choice in barrett\u2019s esophagus",
        "Option 1":"Esophagectomy and histopathology",
        "Option 2":"Ultrasonography",
        "Option 3":"CT scan",
        "Option 4":"Endoscopy and biopsy",
        "Option 5":"PET scan",
        "Correct Answer":"Endoscopy and biopsy"
    }
]